My view was that part of the role of the presidency is to constantly remind
us of the ties that bind us together.
And we live in a big,complicated,raucous,diverse nation.
I've said before,I believe,it is what makes us exceptional.
There's never been an experiment like this where you have people from every corner of
the globe show up in one place and say,
based on these ideals,
we hold these truths to be self-evident.
All men are created equal.
that based on that and a Constitution and a Bill of Rights and a democracy
that we can somehow figure out how to get along and maintain our private beliefs
and pray to God in our own ways and retain aspects of the cultures that
we bring from wherever it is that we're coming from and yet still decide that
we are all Americans who can salute that flag and believe in a certain creed
and defend this country and try to make it better for each successive generation.
And I'm not alone in that belief.
As I said,I think George W.
Bush believed that.
I believe that people who I ran against,I know John McCain believed it.
I know Mitt Romney believed it.
So what I'm describing is not a Democratic value or a Republican value.
It is an American value.